<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../schemata/shelley-godwin-page.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="../../../schemata/shelley-godwin-page.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:mith="http://mith.umd.edu/sc/ns1#"
  ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="5354" lry="7080"
  xml:id="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0001" partOf="#ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4"
  mith:shelfmark="MS. Shelley adds. c. 4" mith:folio="Notes written on front of first fasicule">
  <graphic url="http://shelleygodwinarchive.org/images/ox/ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0001.jp2"/>
  <zone type="library"><line rend="right">Shelley-Rolls Folders 1-4</line></zone>
  <zone type="left_margin">
    <space dim="vertical" unit="lines" extent="15"/>
    <line>*clasp</line><line>added</line><line>19-iii-1986</line></zone>
  <zone type="main">
  <line>When Sir John Shelley-Rolls presented MS. Shelley adds. C. 4 to the Bodleian in 1946,</line>
  <line>it comprised a leather box and a series of 'folders' (foolscap bifolia of lined paper)</line>
  <line>which contained Shelley autograph sheets, still loose. The descriptions inscribed</line>
  <line>on the folders are in Sir John's hand. He numbered the folders 1-38, and also</line>
  <line>wrote in numbers in light pencil (sometimes not now legible) in the corners of the</line>
  <line>original leaves themselves. Folders 27, 28 and 31 encompass inner folders</line>
  <line>marked in Lady Shelley's hand (see also 29, unmarked). The handsome box,</line>
  <line>of light brown leather lined with dark red silk, was part of Lady Shelley's</line>
  <line>bequest to Sir John, for the table of contents inset into its inside lid (in the hand</line>
  <line>of an amanuensis of Lady Shelley) is ticked off item by item in pencil with</line>
  <line>Sir John's initials and dates in late January 1901; but this table does not</line>
  <line>correspond to the present contents.</line>
  <line rend="indent1">In Oct. 1985 - Feb. 1986 the loose sheets and folders were mounted into</line>
  <line>standard Bodleian fascicules, and the box was adapted by cutting its</line>
  <line>right-hand side at top and bottom to make a hinged flap.* The foliation</line>
  <line>of 1946 (in which Philip Long, an Assistant in the Dept. of Western Manuscripts,</line>
  <line>numbered original leaves and folders continuously and without distinction)</line>
  <line>has been retained and should be cited as such, although the necessities</line>
  <line>of mounting have dictated some changes of order. Fols. 141-177 and 210-2476 are now</line>
  <line>kept out of sequence at the bottom of the box.<space unit="chars" extent="5"/> B.C.B.-B 13 Feb. 1986 </line>
  </zone>  
  
   
  
</surface>
