<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><?xml-model href="../../../schemata/shelley-godwin-page.rnc"
  type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl"
  href="../../../xsl/page-proof.xsl"?>
<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:mith="http://mith.umd.edu/sc/ns1#"
  ulx="0" uly="0" lrx="4966" lry="7248"
  xml:id="ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0383" partOf="#ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4"
  mith:shelfmark="MS. Shelley adds. c. 4" mith:folio="263b recto">
  <graphic url="http://shelleygodwinarchive.org/images/ox/ox-ms_shelley_adds_c4-0383.jp2"/>
  <zone type="main">
    <line>-tered in <del rend="strikethrough">the country in</del> England.</line>
    <line>The book of Job, or Solomons Song he admires as he admires</line>
    <line>Aeschylus &amp; Anacreon, &amp; considers those models of poetical</line>
    <line>sublimity &amp; pathos, as <del rend="strikethrough">the productions</del> no more than the uninspired</line>
    <line>productions of persons of distinguished genius.</line>
    <line>Nor is there any deciet in this. I neither intend to decive nor</line>
    <line>do I decieve. Sir Samuel Romilly Mr. William Smith are incapable</line>
    <line>of    a solemnn &amp; public imposture. I have thier authority for considering</line>
    <line>it as a mere <del rend="strikethrough">formality</del> ceremony. The oath indeed is said</line>
    <line>some appearance</line>
    <line>A Quakers testimony is indeed rejected &amp; not without</line>
    <line>reason; <del rend="strikethrough">in the common principles which govern the</del></line>
    <line>He denies, as it were the jurisdiction of the</line>
    <line>Court, by refusing to comply with that formality</line>
    <line>in</line>
    <line>which it has been the practise for every other</line>
    <line>British citizen to acquiesce. Besides, he ackno<del rend="strikethrough">wledges</del></line>
    <line>-wledges the divine authority of that code, on which</line>
    <line>he is nevertheless unwilling to pledge the truth of</line>
    <line>might be interpreted into the</line>
    <line>his statement. This <del rend="strikethrough">looks like</del>, leaving himself</line>
    <line>through</line>
    <line>a loophole, <del rend="strikethrough">from</del> which to escape. - Th<del rend="strikethrough">at</del>e truth is</line>
    <line>that Jesus Christ in express words forbade swearig</line>
    <line>at all, &amp; this the Quaker knows. This is not the</line>
    <line>occasion for proving how futile are the grounds on</line>
    <line>which the Quakers testimony is rejected, - it was</line>
    <line>is</line>
    <line>a</line>
    <line>of education</line>
    <line>only necessary to shew that the same arguments</line>
    <line>which have been used to exclude the Quaker from his rights as a witness or</line>
  </zone>
</surface>
