<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://shelleygodwinarchive.org"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>The Shelley-Godwin Archive</title>
 <link>http://shelleygodwinarchive.org</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>University of Maryland S-GA Press Release</title>
 <link>http://shelleygodwinarchive.org/sga-press-release</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
October 18, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT’S ALIVE! SHELLEY-GODWIN DIGITAL ARCHIVE &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UMD partners with New York Public Library and the Bodleian to digitize original Shelley family manuscripts, starting with Mary Shelley’s iconic &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COLLEGE PARK, Md.&lt;/strong&gt; – The University of Maryland’s Institute for Technology in the Humanities (MITH) announces the launch of the Shelley-Godwin Archive (SG-A), a new digital resource that allows scholars, students and the public to explore in one place the widely scattered texts of England’s “first family of writers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first time together, the archive will make available online the manuscripts of Mary Wollstonecraft, William Godwin, Percy Bysshe Shelley and Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley. The public can take a deeper look into the creative process of literature’s most iconic texts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on MITH’s leadership and innovation in the field of digital humanities, the technology driving the archive provides high-quality, zoomable page images, as well as transcriptions of each page created on the fly from TEI-encoding. The first public release of the archive will be the fully transcribed and encoded manuscripts of Mary Shelley’s Frankenstein notebooks, the page images for which have been provided by the Bodleian Library at Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those interested in Frankenstein will now be able to investigate for the first time online its complex evolution as a literary work and the relative roles of both Mary and Percy Shelley in its creation, about which there has been much controversy,” said Neil Fraistat from MITH. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users will search and see for themselves insertions, deletions, shifts in hand, and other variables related to the composition process. Future archive releases will encourage “participatory digital humanities,” which aims to provide web-based tools that help the archive function as a work-site for scholars, students, and the general public. Contributions will come in the form of transcriptions, corrections, annotations and TEI encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This project is an excellent answer to the persistent question about what research looks like in the humanities,” said Bonnie Thornton Dill, UMD’s dean of the College of Arts and Humanities. “The archive unwraps the Frankenstein’s complex explorations of gender roles alongside newly uncovered evidence of the author’s own complex personal and professional relationships.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The archive was made possible by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and was created in partnership with the Bodleian Libraries of the University of Oxford and the New York Public Library’s Carl H. Pforzheimer Collection of Shelley and His Circle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Shelley-Godwin Archive, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shelleygodwinarchive.org&quot;&gt;www.shelleygodwinarchive.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities (MITH) is a leading digital humanities center that pursues disciplinary innovation and institutional transformation through applied research, public programming, and educational opportunities. Jointly supported by the University of Maryland College of Arts and Humanities and the University of Maryland Libraries, MITH engages in collaborative, interdisciplinary work at the intersection of technology and humanistic inquiry. MITH specializes in text and image analytics for cultural heritage collections, data curation, digital preservation, linked data applications, and data publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the University of Maryland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The University of Maryland is the state’s flagship university and one of the nation&#039;s preeminent public research universities. A global leader in research, entrepreneurship and innovation, Maryland is ranked No. 21 among public universities by U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report and No. 14 among public universities by Forbes. The Institute of Higher Education, which ranks the world’s top universities based on research, puts Maryland at No. 38 in the world, No. 29 nationally and No. 13 among U.S. public research institutions. The university is also one of the top 10 highest-rated D.C.-area employers, according to Glassdoor.com. Its faculty includes three Nobel laureates, two Pulitzer Prize winners, 49 members of the national academies and scores of Fulbright scholars. The university is recognized for its diversity, with underrepresented students comprising one-third of the student population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 16:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>stephanie-sapienza</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">16 at http://shelleygodwinarchive.org</guid>
 <comments>http://shelleygodwinarchive.org/sga-press-release#comments</comments>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
